NATANAEL TAMBUN

 $Toba, Sumatra\ Utara\ |\ +62\ 812-7889-9259\ |\ tambunnatana el 55@gmail.com\ |\ \underline{https://www.linkedin.com/in/natana el-tambun7a15a1227}$

ABOUT ME

I graduated with a degree in Information Systems. I have experience in web development, full-stack development, data mining, and data visualization. Currently, I am particularly interested in web development and testing, as well as data analysis. I am currently employed at PT. Digital Sinergi Kreatif Berkarya as a web developer.

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

PT Digital Sinergi Kreatif Berkarya (Medan)

Web Developer (February 2024 – Present)

- Tasked with building and developing web platforms for companies operating in the IT sector. which can later be used to make ordering easier, for example when ordering digital invitations, cakes, florists. This final project uses selenium python for scrapping and python for data processing.
- Working in a company that has several partners in Medan

Final Project – Sentiment Analysis of Instagram Comments about the 2024 Presidential Election to Describe Public Perception

IT Del (Sept 2022 – Jun 2023)

- This final project aims to determine the sentiment analysis from the public for the presidential election which will be held in 2024 with the data used sourced from Instagram comments.
- To collect Instagram comment data, it is used by scraping within a predetermined time period, then the data is processed using Python to produce a number of sentiments.
- This final project uses selenium python for scrapping and python for data processing.

Internships – System Monitoring History AP Down

Web Developer at PT Telkom Medan (Jun 2022 - Sep 2022)

- A web application that was built with the aim of helping monitoring AP Up and AP Down on a wifi network.
- Participated in all aspect of a project, from design and development to testing.
- Using Laravel, PostgreSQL, Postman testing API and hosting projects on MyDomaiNesia.

Information System Project – Traveleo Tour Car Rental Information System

Web Developer (Sept 2020 - Dec 2022)

- A web car rental application built for Traveleo Tour and Travel companies, this website was built with the aim of helping the car ordering process if someone wants to make a rental.
- Using PHP Laravel, Bootstrap framework, PostgreSQL.

Web Application Programming and Testing - Nwitee

Back End Developer (Sept 2021 - Dec 2021)

- Build web applications that aid students in getting information and serve as a forum for discussion. It can also facilitate the flow of ideas in a restricted space, as well as increase the student network by allowing users to interact with one another and learn about the activities of other users.
- Participated in all aspect of a project, from design and development to testing.
- Using Laravel.

ORGANIZATIONS

Member | Bebras Biro IT Del - Publication Divison

Oct 2020 - jan 2021

- Making Workshop Computational Thinking poster for Teacher, and making certificates for all the participants.
- Participate in material presentation activities via zoom to participants.

Participant – UX Design, Gemastik

Jun 2021 - Jul 2021

- Designing an interface and a good user experience using related methods, so that the results of application design that have good UX quality.
- Use figma as a tool.

EDUCATION

Del Institute of Technology - Indonesia

Aug 2019 – sept 2023

Bachelor Degree in Information System | GPA 2.97/4.00

SKILLS

Hard Skills: Basic Java | HTML | CSS | PHP | Laravel Framework | Bootstrap Framework | SQL Server

Management Studio | Postman | Mongo DB | Visual Studio Code | Heidi SQL | Git | GitHub | Sublime |

Eclipse.

Soft Skills: Communication Skills, Collaboration, Problem-Solving, Adaptability, Time Management.